Keshav Raj

keshav.rajsspn@gmail.com | +91-9576640200 | linkedin.com/in/k-e-s-h-a-v | github.com/k-e-s-h-a-v

SUMMARY

Ambitious Data Engineer with 3+ years of experience in building high-performance data platforms, specializing in decentralized architectures (DataMesh) with Data Governance and optimizing business intelligence systems. Successfully led teams, was quick to adapt to challenging environments and contributed to product acquisition

EDUCATION

Bhagalpur College of Engineering, Bhagalpur

Jul 2018 - Sept 2022

B. Tech in Electrical Engineering

CGPA: 8.2

Sainik School Punglwa Nagaland, Ministry of Defence

May 2010 - June 2017

Science, High School Education

Percentage: 81.2

EXPERIENCE

Infor Jul 2024 - Present

Hyderabad, India

Software Engineer

 Jul 2024 - Present
 Integrated Apache Superset using Delta Lake to the DataMesh platform for real-time data visualization.

Built an invoice processing system with Qwen to extract data that feeds an event-driven, configurable data entry pipeline, reducing SLA from 48 hours to 1.5 minutes.

albanero (acquired by Infor) Jun 2021 - Jul 2024

Hyderabad, India

• Software Engineer II (6 months)

Jan 2024 - Jul 2024

- Key contributor to a **state-of-the-art DataMesh platform**, later acquired by Infor.
- \circ Slashed memory usage by 90% in the CSV-to-Excel pipeline. eg: 52 GB to 4 GB for ≈ 3 million records.
- Enabled multi-CSV merging into a single Excel file, with each CSV as a dedicated sheet.
- Team Lead (8 months)

May 2023 - Jan 2024

- Led a team of data analysts to deliver high-impact products, including two key projects—one was live in just
 6 weeks.
- Built a data mastering system using the Jaro-Winkler algorithm for duplicate detection.
- Standardized entity names using **NER** with **spaCy**, and integrated **Loqute** for **address verification**.
- Conducted internal training sessions on our **DataMesh platform**, teaching teams how to use its **decentralized** architecture and scalable workflows.
- Software Engineer I (8 months)

Sep 2022 - May 2023

- Built a dynamic **SQL** query generator to search/filter millions of records.
- Software Engineer Intern (1 year 4 months)

Jun 2021 - Sep 2022

- o Developed Identity Access Management (IAM) for DataMesh, including role-permission logic.
- Authored feature for real-time status updates for data transformation workflows using Socket.io.
- Implemented **multi-theme support** in a **SaaS platform**, standardized **SCSS practices**, and gained hands-on experience with **JavaScript**.

PROJECTS

• Explorer++ $\boldsymbol{\mathscr{G}}$

Visual Studio Code Extension

• Code Folder Summary •

Visual Studio Code Extension

• FS++•

Visual Studio Code Extension

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, SQL, JavaScript

Libraries/Frameworks: PySpark, FastAPI, Flask, Docker

BI/Analytics Tools: Apache Superset, AWS Athena, Delta Lake (Parquet), MongoDB

Tech: Git, Data Modeling, ETL Pipelines, Data Security, Data Federation

CERTIFICATES

An Introduction to Artificial Intelligence ${\mathfrak G}$ Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms using Python ${\mathfrak G}$ Data Analytics at E & ICT Academy ${\mathfrak G}$

IIT Delhi IIT Madras

IIT Kanpur